Finding Aid for Democratic Party of Michigan records, 1932-2008
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- State Chair, Democratic State Central Committee files
  - State Chairman File-F. Thomas Lewand (1989)
    - Michigan Democratic County Officials Steering Committee 1989 (Box 45)
    - Michigan Democratic Party Leadership Meetings 1990 (Box 45)
    - Michigan Democratic Party Personnel Policy Guidelines 1989 (Box 45)
    - Michigan Democratic Party Staff (Box 45)
    - General 1989 (Box 45)
    - Meetings 1989 (Box 45)
    - Michigan Democratic Party Update 1989 (Box 45)
    - Michigan Politicians 1989 (Box 45)
    - Michigan Young Democrats 1989 (Box 45)
    - Michigan State University Democrats 1989 (Box 45)
    - Outreach 1989 (Box 45)
    - Party Platform 1990 (Box 45)
    - Phone Bank 1989 (Box 45)
    - Policy Committee 1989 (Box 45)
    - Policy Conference 1990 (Box 45)
    - Press Releases 1989 (Box 45)
    - Proposal "A" 1990 (Box 45)
    - Proposal "A" Ballot Spin 1989 (Box 45)
    - Public Relations 1989 (Box 45)
    - Raby, Anita 1989 (Box 45)
    - Reapportionment 1988-1989 (Box 45)
    - Reapportionment Correspondence 1989 (Box 45)
    - Resolutions 1989 (Box 45)
    - Rules-Michigan Democratic Party 1989 (Box 45)
    - Saginaw County 1989 (Box 45)
    - Secretary of State Contract Cancellation 1989 (Box 45)
    - Second District 1989 (Box 45)
    - Staff Memos 1989 (Box 45)
    - State Central Committee, Report to 1989 (Box 45)
    - State Party Planning 1989 (Box 45)
    - Telemarketing (Dollars for Democrats) 1989, 2 folders (Box 45)
    - United Auto Workers 1989 (Box 45)
    - Voter Database-Vendor Agreement 1989 (Box 45)
    - Wayne County Census 1990 (Box 45)
    - Weekly Reports 1989 (Box 45)
    - Youth Outreach 1989 (Box 45)
    - Youth Recruiting 1989 (Box 45)
  - State Chairman Files-Gary Corbin 1991-1992
    - Administrative
      - Bingo (Shelden Hall) (Box 45)
      - Bommarito, Sharon (Box 45)
      - Calendar of Events; 1991-1992 (Box 45)
      - Committees
        - Appeals (Box 45)
        - Policy and Resolutions (Box 45)
      - Corbin, Gary
        - Biography (Box 45)
        - Speeches/Remarks (Box 45)
      - Debt (Box 45)
      - Exit Memos (Box 45)
      - Fund-Raising (Box 45)
      - Holcomb, Tom (Box 45)
      - Leadership Meetings (Box 45)
      - Party Development (Box 45)
      - Rules of Michigan Democratic Party (Box 45)
    - Association of State Democratic Chairs
      - Correspondence (Box 45)
      - Meetings
        - March 22, 1991 (Box 45)
        - September 20-21, 1991 (Box 45)
        - November 21-23, 1991 (Box 45)
    - Campaigns and Elections
      - Board of State Canvassers (Box 45)
      - Coordinated Campaign 1992 (Box 45)
      - "Democratic Defection" Report (Box 45)
      - "Marketing the Democratic Presidential Primary" Proposal (Box 45)
      - Opinion Poll 1992 (Box 45)
      - "The People, the Press & Politics: Campaign '92" Survey Results (Box 45)
    - Campaigns and Elections
      - Primaries (Box 45)
      - State Convention (Box 45)
    - Congressional Districts and Affiliates
      - Chippewa County (Box 45)
      - County Officers (Box 45)
      - Hillsdale County (Box 45)
      - Houghton County (Box 45)
      - Ingham County (Box 45)
      - Lapeer County (Box 45)
      - Michigan Democratic County Officials (Box 45)
      - Questionnaire (Box 45)
      - Sixteenth Democratic Congressional District (Box 45)
      - St. Clair County (Box 45)
      - Young Democrats (Box 45)
    - Correspondence
      - Appreciation (Box 45)
      - Citizens' Concerns (selections), 2 folders (Box 45)
      - Congratulations (Box 45)
      - Invitations (selections) (Box 45)
      - Newsletters (Box 45)
    - Democratic National Committee
      - Administration (Box 46)
      - Correspondence (Box 46)
      - Delegate Selection
        - Democratic National Committee Plan (Box 46)
        - Michigan Plan (Box 46)
      - Meetings
        - June 30, 1990 (Box 46)
        - September 14-15, 1990 (Box 46)
        - March 22-23, 1991 (Box 46)
        - September 20-21, 1991 (Box 46)
        - November 21, 1991 (Box 46)
        - February 29, 1992 (Box 46)
        - July 13-16, 1992 (Box 46)
      - Newsletters (Box 46)
      - Resolutions (Box 46)
    - Legislation
      - Apportionment (Box 46)
      - Dodak, Speaker Lewis (Box 46)
      - Elliott-Larsen Civil Rights Act (Box 46)
      - Headlee Tax Cut Initiative (Box 46)
      - House Appropriations (Box 46)
      - Michigan Black Legislative Caucus (Box 46)
      - Michigan Budget Critique (Box 46)
      - Michigan Budget Proposal (Box 46)
      - Michigan Homeowners Tax Break (Box 46)
      - Michigan House Democrats Report 1992 (Box 46)
      - Opinion Poll 1991 (Box 46)
      - Property Tax Cut Plan (Box 46)
      - Public Opinion Monitor (Box 46)
      - Senate Bill 691 (No-Fault Auto Insurance) (Box 46)
      - Term Limitation (Box 46)
      - Wayne County Redistricting (Box 46)
    - Projects & Events
      - Century Fund (Box 46)
      - Field Recommendations (Box 46)
      - Focus on Youth (Box 46)
      - Issues Forum (Box 46)
      - Jefferson-Jackson Day (Box 46)
      - Michigan Voter File (Box 46)
      - Party-Building Workshop (Box 46)
      - President's Club (Box 46)
      - Training Cycle 1991 (Box 46)
    - Topical file 1991-1994
      - Committee Assignments 1991 (Box 47)
      - Delegate selection information 1992 (Box 47)
      - Democratic Leadership Council (Box 47)
      - Economy subcommittee 1991-1992 (Box 47)
      - Election calendar 1992 (Box 47)
      - Jonker, Nate (Box 47)
      - Kerrey, Sen. Robert (Box 47)
      - Carol Koistra 1993-1994 (Box 47)
      - Leadership Meetings (Box 47)
      - Membership Letter 1991 (Box 47)
      - Membership Meeting May 2, 1991 (Box 47)
      - Michigan Democratic Party Planning February 1991 (Box 47)
      - Natural Resources subcommittee 1991-1992 (Box 47)
      - North Macomb Democratic Club (Box 47)
      - Party Officers (Box 47)
      - Presidential Primary 1990 (Box 47)
      - Presidential Primary / Secretary of State 1991 (Box 47)
      - Press Releases January-May 1991 (Box 47)
      - Press releases 1992 (Box 47)
      - Property Tax Cut (Box 47)
      - Property Tax Relief Plan (Box 47)
      - Reapportionment 1991 (Box 47)
      - Reapportionment Correspondence 1991 (Box 47)
      - Redistricting Guidelines for State Legislature (Box 47)
      - Redistricting Testimony (G. Corbin) 1991 (Box 47)
      - Jay Rockefeller Meeting July 1991 (Box 47)
      - Rules and Political Reform Committee 1991 (Box 47)
      - Secretary of State 1991 (Box 47)
      - Speeches (Box 47)
      - Staff Memos 1991 (Box 47)
      - Task Force Draft Bill HR 3750 November 1991 (Box 47)
      - Temporary Standing Committee Members (Box 47)
      - Term Limitations January-February 1992 (Box 47)
      - Victory '92 Banners / Time Series 1992 (Box 47)
      - Voter Files (Box 47)
    - Chairman's Correspondence 1992-1994 (Box 47)
- Other Staff Positions
  Also of great importance are the records of Other Party Officers. These include: vice chair Adelaide Hart covering her activities 1959 to 1966 (note: there is also a separately cataloged collection of Adelaide Hart papers) and deputy chair Robert Mitchell covering his work 1971-1973. The work of Olivia Maynard is well represented in this series, as vice chair 1969-1977; party secretary 1968-1971, and as a member of the party's policy committee. Other staff positions found in this series include directors of public information Morgan O'Leary and Thomas Gray for the years 1968-1976; the Press/Publicity Division, 1965-1981; and executive director Tom Boyd files, 1990-1995.
  - Vice-chair (Adelaide Hart)
    - Topical file 1961-1966
      - Campaign Conference, Washington, DC April 1966 (Box 48)
      - Candidates (Gubernatorial) 1965 (Box 48)
      - Conventions
        - State convention
          - 1964 (Box 48)
          - 1965 (Box 48)
            (See also Issues)
        - Wayne County Convention 1966 (Box 48)
      - Dollars for Democrats 1961-1962, 2 folders (Box 48)
      - Eighteen Years Old Voting Age 1964 (Box 48)
      - Fair share
        - 1963 (Box 48)
        - 1966 (Box 48)
      - Finances-Party 1962 (Box 48)
      - "4 for '64", 2 folders (Box 48)
      - Hart, Senator Philip A. (Box 8)
      - Issues, Michigan State Convention 1965 (Box 48)
      - Jefferson-Jackson (Jeff-Jack) Day Dinner
        - 1966 (Federation of Democratic Women, March 26) (Box 48)
      - Johnson, Lyndon) Dinner June 1964 (Box 48)
      - John F. Kennedy House Fund (Box 48)
      - Membership drives
        - 1963 (Box 48)
        - 1964 (Box 48)
        - 1966 (Box 48)
      - Nationalities 1963-1964 (Box 48)
      - State Day 1962 (Box 48)
      - Teen Dems 1965 (Box 48)
      - Women
        - 1959
          - Democratic Women's Day April 1959, 2 folders (Box 48)
          - Democratic Women's Day October 1959 (Box 48)
        - 1960
          - Democratic Women's Day (Strategy for Peace) (Box 48)
        - 1961
          - Activities, General (Box 48)
          - Women's Day May 6, 1961 (Box 48)
        - 1962
          - Campaign Conference for Democratic Women (Box 48)
          - Democratic Women's Day January 27, 1962 (Box 48)
          - Democratic Women's Day Rally November 2, 1962 (Box 48)
          - Mobilization Committee (Box 48)
          - State Convention, Fashion in Politics (Box 48)
          - Wayne County Women's Activities, Coffee Hour Mobilization (Box 48)
          - Women's T.V. Fund (Box 48)
        - 1964
          - Washington's Women's Conference April-May 1964 (Box 48)
        - 1965
          - Women Vote on expenditures (Box 48)
          - Democratic Woman's Day (Box 48)
      - Young Dems
        - Correspondence
          - 1961-1962 (Box 48)
          - 1963-1965 (Box 48)
          - 1965-1966 (Box 48)
  - Deputy Chairman (Robert Mitchell)
    - Topical file 1971-1973
      - Agriculture (Box 49)
      - Agriculture Committee (Box 49)
      - Anti-Semitism (Box 49)
      - Appeals Committee (Box 49)
      - Bobwatchers (i.e. Robert Griffin) (Box 49)
      - Bylaws 1970 (Box 49)
      - Democratic Convention 1972 (Box 49)
      - Democratic Legislative Campaign Committee (Box 49)
      - Democratic National Committee (Box 49)
      - Democratic State Central Committee, 2 folders (Box 49)
      - Education-Better Education/Sound Taxation (BEST), Program of February 16, 1972 (Box 49)
      - Election reform (Box 49)
      - Employee 1972 campaign (Box 49)
      - Front Lash (Box 49)
      - Fund Raisers (Box 49)
      - Highways (Box 49)
      - Indians (Box 49)
      - Interns (Box 49)
      - Issue Development Committee (Box 49)
      - Leadership newsletter (Box 49)
      - Lee, Bob (Box 49)
      - Legislation 1971 (Box 49)
      - Legislative Conference (Box 49)
      - Letters of interest (Box 49)
      - Memberships 1970-1973, 4 folders (Box 49)
      - Memoranda to staff 1972 (Box 49)
      - Michigan Register and Vote Committee 1968-1972, 9 folders (Box 49)
      - Midwest Conference (Box 49)
      - Platform 1970 (Box 49)
      - Policy Committee 1971, 1973, 2 folders (Box 49)
      - Political Reform 1969-1972, 3 folders (Box 49)
      - Presidential race 1972 (Box 50)
      - Press releases 1972 (include Michigan Democratic Party News) (Box 50)
      - Quality Education Committee 1971 (Box 50)
      - Resolutions (Box 50)
      - Senate races 1972 (Box 50)
      - Small loans (Box 50)
      - Special election (54th district, Michigan House of Representative) 1971 (Box 50)
      - State convention 1972 (Box 50)
      - Tax reform 1974, 2 folders (Box 50)
      - Telethon II 1973 (Box 50)
      - Television (requests for equal time) (Box 50)
      - Think Tank (Box 50)
      - TV 72 (Total Victory) (Box 50)
      - Unicameral legislature (Box 50)
      - United Farm Workers (Box 50)
      - Veterans (Box 50)
      - Veterans Committee (Box 50)
      - VIP analysis meeting 1970 (Box 50)
      - VIP Program 1970, 1972, 2 folders (Box 50)
      - Voter motivation survey 1969 (Box 50)
      - Young Democrats (Box 50)
      - Youth Officers (Box 50)
      - Youth Registration Drive 1971 (Box 50)
      - Youth Workshops 1971 (Box 50)
  - Vice Chair (Olivia Maynard)
    - Topical file 1969-1972
      - Abortion reform and legislation (Box 50)
      - Agriculture Committee (Box 50)
      - Bi-Partisan pledge against racism in campaigning (Box 50)
      - Calhoun County (Box 50)
      - Continuing Political Reform Committee (Box 50)
      - Democratic State Central Committee (Box 50)
      - Districts/district committees (Box 50)
      - Fall Conferences 1971 (Box 50)
      - Genesee County Democratic Party (Box 50)
      - Indian Rights Committee (Box 50)
      - Indians, 2 folders (Box 50)
      - Kleiner Committee (re apportionment) (Box 50)
      - Leadership (minutes of meetings, etc.) (Box 50)
      - McGovern visit to Michigan September 1971 (Box 51)
      - Maynard campaign for vice chair (Box 51)
      - Membership reports 1971-1972, 2 folders (Box 51)
      - Midwest Conference (Box 51)
      - Mississippi (Box 51)
      - National Committee (Box 51)
      - Neutrality statement, governor's campaign 1970 (Box 51)
      - People's Liberation (Box 51)
      - Political Reform Convention January 1970
        - General file (Box 51)
        - Amendments (Box 51)
        - Convention Planning Rules Committee (Box 51)
        - Credentials Committee (Box 51)
        - Plenary sessions (Box 51)
        - Rules committee (Box 51)
      - Registration (Box 51)
      - Robo form responses 1972-1973, 2 folders (Box 51)
      - Staff responsibilities (Box 51)
      - Taxation (Box 51)
      - United Farm Workers (Box 51)
      - Vader, Elnora (Box 51)
      - Veterans (Box 51)
      - Wayne County Democratic Committee (Box 51)
      - Youth (Box 51)
      - Youth officers (Box 51)
  - Vice Chair (Olivia Maynard) (include some Mary Bethany, Coordinator, papers)
    - Topical file 1973-1977
      - Coe Township Democratic Club (Box 51)
      - Eighth Congressional District correspondence (Box 51)
      - Election night activities (Box 51)
      - Gray, Tom (Box 51)
      - Jeff-Jack workshops information (Box 51)
      - Kelly, Frank for U.S. Senate 1972 (Box 51)
      - Levin, Sander for Governor 1974 (Box 51)
      - Libby Maynard file (Box 51)
      - Membership drive 1973 (for 1974) (Box 51)
      - Personnel Policy, Professional and Clerical (Box 51)
      - Policy Committee 1973
        - General material, 3 folders (Box 51)
        - Agriculture, Ecology and Environment Subcommittee (Barbara Sawyer, field staff member), files, 3 folders (Box 52)
        - Environment and Consumerism Subcommittee (Box 52)
      - Polling information
        - General file 1974 (Box 52)
        - Breakdown 1974 (Box 52)
        - Sample poll (Box 52)
      - Press releases 1974 (Box 52)
      - Resolutions
        - County/District (Box 52)
        - Referred to the Policy Committee (Box 52)
      - Talent (Box 52)
      - Upper Peninsula trip 1977 (Box 52)
  - Secretary (Olivia Maynard)
    - Topical file 1968-1971
      - ABM Committee 1969 (Box 52)
      - County Executive Committee
        - General file 1968-1970 (Box 52)
        - Election Evaluation (Box 52)
        - Officers 1968-1970 (Box 52)
        - County officers 1971 (Box 52)
        - District officers 1970 (Box 52)
      - Democratic State Convention 1968 (Box 52)
  - Director of Public Information (Morgan O'Leary/Thomas Gray)
    - Background files 1968-1972
      - A.B.M. 1969 (Box 53)
      - Abortion (Box 53)
      - Budget (State) 1968-1969 (Box 53)
      - Busing 1972 (Box 53)
      - Campaign- 1968
        - General (Box 53)
        - Legislative candidates (Box 53)
        - V-68 Receptions (Box 53)
      - Fair housing 1968 (Box 53)
      - Campaign finances 1971 (Box 53)
      - Campaign materials 1972 (Box 53)
      - Citizenship Participation Programs report (Box 53)
      - Civil service (Box 53)
      - Computerized registration (Box 53)
      - Conference of Concerned Democrats 1968 (Box 53)
      - Convention, Spring 1969 (Box 53)
      - County newsletters (Box 53)
      - Crime (Box 53)
      - Democratic chairman election 1969 (Box 53)
      - Democratic goals for the 70s (Box 53)
      - Democratic Legislative Campaign Committee 1971 (Box 53)
      - Democratic Policy Committee 1971 (Box 53)
      - Democratic State Central Committee, 2 folders (Box 53)
      - Democratic State Party budget 1971 (Box 53)
      - Detroit Free Press (party's objection to article) (Box 53)
      - Education reform (Box 53)
      - Edwards, George (Box 53)
      - Election analysis 1970 (Box 53)
      - Electoral College luncheon 1969 (Box 53)
      - Fairness Doctrine-TV (Box 53)
      - Field Reports (Box 53)
      - Finance Committee (Box 53)
      - Florescu, Stefan (Box 53)
      - Gun control 1968 (Box 53)
      - Hines, Gail Hamilton (Box 53)
      - House Candidates (Box 53)
      - Ideas-Party Organization (Box 53)
      - Jefferson-Jackson Day Dinner speech 1968 (Box 53)
      - Jefferson-Jackson Day Dinner speech 1969 (Box 53)
      - Jefferson-Jackson Day Dinner program 1971 (Box 53)
      - John Fitzgerald Kennedy House dedication program (Box 53)
      - Knight, John S. (Box 53)
      - Labor-Labor Law (Box 53)
      - Law Enforcement (Box 53)
      - Leadership Meetings (Box 53)
      - Levin, Sander M. (Box 53)
      - McCarthy, Eugene (Box 53)
      - McGovern Commission 1969 (Box 53)
        (Democratic National Committee's Commission on Party Structure and Delegate Selection)
      - McNeely, James
        - General file (Box 53)
        - 1969 press file (Box 53)
      - Mail participation (Box 53)
      - Membership (Box 53)
      - Memoranda (O'Leary) (Box 53)
      - Mentally retarded (Box 53)
      - Michigan Democrat (publication) (Box 53)
      - Michigan Democrats (Box 53)
      - Michigan Welfare League (speech by Sander M. Levin) (Box 53)
      - New Democratic Coalition (Box 53)
      - Nixon dollars (Box 53)
      - Officers' meetings (Box 53)
      - O'Neil, Joseph E. (Box 53)
      - Political Reform Commission, 2 folders (Box 53)
      - Presidential Primary (Box 54)
      - Public Relations (Box 54)
      - Quality education (Box 54)
      - Resolutions (Box 54)
      - Romney, George (Box 54)
      - Speeches, miscellaneous (Box 54)
      - Staff meetings (Box 54)
      - State Central Committee
        - Meetings (Box 54)
        - Chairman's reports (Box 54)
      - Television (Box 54)
      - Upper Peninsula Democrats (Box 54)
      - Urban Affairs (Box 54)
      - Vietnam (Box 54)
      - Voter Motivation Study (Box 54)
      - Wallace, George (Box 54)
      - Youth (Box 54)
    - Election/campaign files 1970-1972
      - Democratic National Convention 1972, 2 folders (Box 54)
      - Election Analysis 1970 Gene Kolb (Box 54)
      - Field activities February 1972 (Box 54)
      - Presidential Primary bill (Box 54)
      - Press releases
        - 1971 (Box 54)
        - 1972 (Box 54)
      - Wallace meeting (account of meeting held March 6, 1972) (Box 54)
    - Election/campaign files 1973-1974
      - Campaign 1974
        - General file (Box 54)
        - Literature (Box 54)
        - Notes for speeches and articles (Box 54)
      - Democratic State Central Committee, annual report and action 1973-1974 (Box 54)
      - Membership drive 1974 (Box 54)
      - Policy Committee 1973-1974 (Box 55)
      - Press releases
        - 1973 (Box 55)
        - 1973-1974 (Box 55)
    - Election/campaign files 1975
      - Correspondence (Box 55)
      - Democratic State Central Committee (Box 55)
      - Leadership newsletter (Box 55)
    - Election/campaign files 1976
      - Correspondence (Box 55)
  - Press/Publicity
    - Topical Files 1965-1981
      - Undated
        - D.S.C.C. Office Library Reference Material (Box 55)
        - Media Lists (Box 55)
        - Michigan Democrat (Box 55)
      - 1965
        - Agriculture (legislation) (Box 55)
      - 1971
        - Agriculture (Box 55)
        - Michigan Democrat (includes postal/circulation statements) (Box 55)
      - 1972
        - Democratic National Party (articles) (Box 55)
      - 1973
        - Capitol: Woman (miscellaneous copies) (Box 55)
        - Democratic National Party (articles) (Box 55)
        - Michigan Democrat (mostly postal/circulation statements) (Box 55)
        - Personnel Practices: D.S.C.C. (Box 55)
        - "Work '73-Win '74" Booklets ("Precinct Organization Handbook"; "Public Relations/Publicity") (Box 55)
      - 1974
        - Agriculture (Box 55)
          (correspondence re: Michigan Agricultural Directory)
        - Damman, James (Box 55)
          (mostly clippings, some news releases, includes undated material)
        - Democratic National Committee Newsletters (Box 55)
        - Democratic National Committee and Democratic National Party (mostly clippings and articles), 2 folders (Box 55)
        - Issues: Public and Legislative (Box 55)
        - Campaign Reforms (mostly clippings) (Box 55)
        - Crime (clippings) (Box 55)
        - Michigan Democrat: includes postal/circulation statements (Box 55)
        - Michigan Democratic Party (clippings) (Box 55)
        - Newsletters/Bulletins: miscellaneous, from national Democratic organizations (Box 55)
        - The Polling Place (miscellaneous copies) (Box 55)
      - 1975
        - Agriculture: schedule of Michigan Democratic Agricultural Committee activities (Box 55)
        - Capitol: Woman (miscellaneous copies) (Box 55)
        - Damman, James (clippings) (Box 55)
        - Democratic National Party and Democratic National Committee (clippings) (Box 55)
        - Democratic National Telethon '75: Democratic National Committee form letters and manual (Box 55)
        - Michigan Democrat: includes postal/circulation statements (Box 55)
        - Personnel Practices: D.S.C.C. (Box 55)
        - The Polling Place (miscellaneous copies) (Box 55)
      - 1976
        - Agriculture: Michigan Democratic Agricultural Committee-annual meeting announcement (Box 55)
        - Conventions and Conferences: Democratic National Convention
          - Arrangements, 2 folders (Box 55)
          - Michigan Delegation
            - General (Box 55)
            - Biographical Information Sheets (Box 55)
            - Selection Process: include news releases, clippings, editorial (Box 56)
        - Fundraising: Potential Party Contributors Lists (lobbyists, etc.) (Box 56)
        - Michigan Democratic: includes postal/circulation statements (Box 56)
        - Michigan Democratic Party (clippings (Box 56)
      - 1977
        - Campaigns and Elections: Campaign Finance Reporting (Box 56)
        - Conventions and Conferences: State Spring Convention (Box 56)
        - County Fairs (Box 56)
        - Damman, James (Box 56)
          (clippings, correspondence between Damman and Winograd)
        - Fundraising: Meet The Michigan Majority (mostly lists of contributors) (Box 56)
        - Issues: Public and Legislative
          - Consumers: clippings and D.S.C.C. "consumergrams" (Box 56)
          - Crime (Box 56)
            (includes Winograd statement to House Judiciary Committee)
          - Education (clippings) (Box 56)
          - Environment and Department of Natural Resources (clippings, articles) (Box 56)
          - Project ELF/Seafarer (clippings) (Box 56)
        - Michigan Democrat: includes postal/circulation statements (Box 56)
        - Michigan Democratic Party (clippings) (Box 56)
        - Personnel Practices (Box 56)
        - Potential Newsletter/Newspaper Topics (Box 56)
        - Public Opinion: polls, reports, news releases, editorials (Box 56)
      - 1978
        - Campaigns and Elections
          - General (mostly clippings) (Box 56)